number 20 okay number 20 I put I took me
a long time I found our photo of
somebody putting water in a good cup of
coffee and ruining it I don't know if
you've ever had somebody do not you know
like they have enough coffee for three
cups and four people show up and my mom
used to do this she had four boys and no
husband around and she got paid on
Friday on Saturday we had orange juice
on Sunday we had half orange juice and
half water on Mondays one third or third
there's like horse pee okay and and
there's a refuge tradition which is
don't water down your refuge okay
like don't mix other stuff into it you
know okay like you hear things from
people you know like I like this idea
that you can fix him air conditioner by
helping other people with their air
conditioner and it's the people who say
but after that okay but you know that's
a nice idea but no no let's be practical
all right you know some of I understand
that the Dahmer point of view but tell
me the practical point of view you know
they got to look at them and say the
dime the point is you know again people
say do practical don't go to love em all
the time
I want to make motors I want to have a
successful relationship I want to be
healthy you know it is this is the most
practical thing this is the thing that
works okay so don't let down water down
your reference like 50% refuse 30%
refuge okay I trust if I help other
people I'll have a good a good business
but you know I kind of have to cheat
people now to get there now you don't
know how many people tell me I mean they
don't say it like that but but they mean
that you know and when we get to this
section in book later it's a hard
section because he's very critical of
things that don't work you know and he
chooses some other worldviews that were
in his country in his life in his time
like there was a there was a world year
called birth
people called bone bone poll but it's
called burn okay and they believed that
the world was created by this person and
they had a they had a belief they still
exist and some people told this Lama you
know my parents were burned they
believed the world was made by shim
bottom and so I kind of like to be 50/50
is that okay
like how all six other people's air
conditioners but also make a parody
symbol you know
it's that okay you know and he says well
if you keep doing that it's like orange
juice you know it's just not going to be
very strong the refuge won't be very
strong okay so it's up to you I don't
mean disrespect your parents I don't
mean that I go to church I went to
church a couple weeks ago and it makes
my family happy and and I learned good
things I learned some good things you
know and that's okay but keep your keep
your worldview protect your worldview
don't water it down don't put water and
good good Starbucks cup of coffee okay
everything's coming from me 100% don't
be a 50% comes from me 50% comes from
something else okay
I mean keep that deal I have a close
Christian friends they said can i still
can I still pray to God I said yeah no
problem
coming from you you know that's okay how
can a person come from me and take care
of me you made your mother you made your
father you know it's possible it's okay
in Buddhism we say Biagio Guinea made
the world okay but I made by Georgina
okay that's okay okay but but below it
is this belief that everything comes
from you and how you treat other people
okay and I don't think it's contradicts
most of the great religions if you study
the 30 pages of the New Testament
Jesus's words we didn't like pull out
this whole conversation about planting
seeds on rocky soil or good soil
and he's talking about seeds all the
time you know and that's the main thing
and Mohammed was the same so no problem
Mayo and key okay but don't put water in
your okay cuz it won't help you okay
everything comes from you everything
comes from how you treat other people
everything is your fault okay okay all
right so I guess during that meditation
you might think about you know are you
watering down your understanding about
seeds you know do you how much do you
believe a cell phone comes from you 30%
25% try that raise the percent try to
struggle your whole life to raise the
percent and it always comes from me and
yours another part of the sentence from
how I treated other people okay it's
always comes from me from how I treated
other people and the building blocks of
existence are not atoms they are
kindnesses okay you got to get there you
got to get to where you you feel that in
your heart you know this computer is not
made of iron atoms and silicon atoms and
copper atoms those atoms are made of
kindness
okay it has copper atoms it has steel
atoms it has aluminum atoms but those
atoms are held together by kindness how
I treat other people okay you got to
reach that place sooner or later in your
life okay
question
[Music]
we'll see when we get there I think it
does yeah I think it does yeah there's a
there's a refuge Val number three which
is after you take refuge in Sangha we
are encouraged not to associate too
closely with people who think this is
all crazy okay not does that mean you
can't have a Christian friend or a
Muslim foreigner it doesn't mean that
what's the sign of good refuge yeah
you're just nice to everybody okay
you don't say oh you you don't believe
copper atoms were made by how you
treated your your your wife's last week
I don't like you you know you know and
you know I pray that this organization
never becomes like that and I don't know
how you know we have to be really
careful you know I taught 18 steps in
the teacher training of how to teach the
pen second-by-second how to teach the
pen it took an hour two hours 18
different things you have to do in a two
minute presentation of the pen you know
and then a week later somebody came up
to me and said I think it's 17 you know
and then suddenly and my mind came this
future thing they'll be the seventeen
steps and religion and they'll be the
eighteen step ten religion and they will
hate each other and they will have war
you know and you know we have to be
careful that it doesn't become like that
okay so this bow it's dangerous the most
dangerous
it means it means you know this was
really hard I mean you have to try to
protect your view of the world from the
whole world okay the whole world
believes copper atoms the whole world
every religion person in the world has
the same religion called science copper
atoms the copper atom copper atom ISM
when everyone is a copper atom is in the
whole world and again then you know try
to spend when you choose your close
friends try to choose friends like I
said Katie's mom Janice when I was
talking about 10 ways to fundraise she
just looking at me like I'm crazy and
I've got really uncomfortable you know I
said are you okay she says yeah I'm okay
so what are you thinking and she said
well isn't helping other people with
their fundraising the way to fundraise
and I'm like you know and you want that
kind of people around you you see that's
all you want to stay close to that kind
of people who can correct you get you
mark off when you have some other idea
you see anything okay
that's all all right